以前在那些即将死去的人身上......
Previously on
Those About to Die...
他们让我想起了你。尤其是那个安德里亚。
They remind me of you.
Especially that Andria.
我看到有一天他会创造整个罗马
I see a day when he's
making all of Rome
忘记你曾经存在过。
forget you ever existed.
执政官马尔苏斯、参议员托雷尔和苏普尔修斯
The Consul Marsus, the
Senators Torel and Supulcius
特此以叛国罪被捕。
are hereby arrested for treason.
但是他做了什么？
But what has he done?
他激起了图密善的敌意。
He has excited the
animus of Domitian.
将与Flamma进行二番战。
There will be a
rematch with Flamma.
再见了，小昆图斯。
Farewell, little Quintus.
小心，小心。
Careful, careful.
注意他的头。
Watch his head.
快点，他来了。
Hurry, he's here.
尼卡，我们来得正是时候。
Nica, we were just in time.
医生。快走！
A physician. Go quick!
加油！来。
Come on! Come.
快点，快点！
Hurry, hurry!
接下来是她的妹妹。
Next, her sister.
你完成了吗？
Are you done?
- 让他以为我死了。- 保持静止。
- Let him think I'm dead.
- Be still.
我尽可能快地来了。
I came as quick as I could.
罂粟酊剂。
Tincture of poppies.
把他的鞋子脱掉。
Get his shoes off.
你将需要它。
You're going to need it.
当我说时，缓慢而稳定地拉动。
When I say, pull
slowly and steadily.
当我说的时候，释放得非常慢。
When I say, release very slowly.
拉。
Pull.
释放。
Release.
准备一些热水。
Prepare some hot water.
发生了什么事情？
What's happening?
-发生了什么事？- 就是那个狗屎诺罗。
- What happened?
- It was that shit Noro.
他设置了他。
He set him up.
他没事。去。
He is all right. Go.
如果他移动，它会解开夹板。
If he moves at all, it
will unset the splint.
然后他会失去一条腿。
Then he'll lose the leg.
如果有必要，就把他绑起来。
Tie him down if you have to.
三碗树脂配酒，早、中、晚。
Three bowls of resin with
wine, morning, noon and night.
他会想要更多。不要给他。
He will want more.
Don't give it to him.
我理解。
I understand.
如果有一丝腐烂的迹象，马上来找我。
If there's a hint of rot,
come get me at once.
诺罗，那条奸诈的狗。
Noro, that treacherous dog.
我早该知道的。
I should have known.
好吧，他现在已经死了。
Well, he's dead now.
对特纳克斯做这件事的人活着，
The one who did
this to Tenax lives,
如果他听说他活了下来，他会回来找他。
and if he hears he has survived,
he will come back for him.
我会派警卫，我可以信任的人。
I'll post guards,
men that I can trust.
好吧，把它们藏起来。
Well, keep them hidden.
让这样做的人认为他已经死了。
Let the one who did
this think he is dead.
现在，去Cispian Hill的公寓，
Now, go to the apartment
on the Cispian Hill,
他把金子放在哪里。
where he's been
putting the gold.
看看它是否还在。
See if it's still there.
我接受特纳克斯的命令，而不是你的命令，女人。
I take orders from Tenax,
not from you, woman.
当他醒来时，
When he wakes,
你愿意我们告诉他吗
would you rather we tell him
我们做了他希望我们做的事，
that we did what he would
have wanted us to do,
或者你做出了所有的决定，无论对错，
or that you made all the
decisions, right or wrong,
大多是错的？
mostly wrong?
好吧。伍拉，过来。
All right. Woola, come.
之后，来到小酒馆。
After that, come to the tavern.
我们像往常一样设置投注。
We set up for
betting like normal.
你去哪了？
Where have you been?
-外。- 通宵达旦。
- Out.
- All night.
看起来是这样。
So it would seem.
发生了什么事？
What happened?
䏃。
Listen carefully.
去酒馆打开它。
Go to the tavern and open it up.
如果有人问起Tenax，
If anyone asks about Tenax,
告诉他们他要去海岸附近买地。
tell them he's away
buying land near the coast.
但让他们认为你在撒谎。
But let them
think you are lying.
我。。。我不明白。
I... I don't understand.
你善于撒谎。
You are good at lying.
假装不擅长。
Pretend to be bad at it.
他的一些敌人需要认为他还活着。
Some of his enemies
need to think him alive.
有些人需要认为他已经死了。
Some need to think him dead.
对特纳克斯这样做的人会急切地对我们做同样的事情。
The man who did that to Tenax
would eagerly do the same to us.
去。
Go.
他走了。
He's gone.
黄金也是如此。
So is the gold.
停。
Stop.
停。请停下来。
Stop. Please, stop.
醒来。醒来，你在梦中。
Wake up. Wake up,
you are in a dream.
你在你的房间里。你很安全。
You're in your
room. You're safe.
当我还是个孩子的时候，我住在一个很棒的家庭里。
I lived with a great
family when I was a boy.
房子的主人，
The master of the house,
他喜欢男孩。
he liked boys.
本人。。。
Myself...
但主要是乌尔苏斯。
But mostly Ursus.
乌尔苏斯。
Ursus.
- 我们是... - 停下来。
- We were...
- Stop.
这是罂粟花的酊剂在说话。
This is tincture
of poppies talking.
不。是我。
No. It's me.
乌尔苏斯和我点燃了一堆火逃跑。
Ursus and I lit
a fire to escape.
我逃走了。
I got away.
但乌尔苏斯被抓住了。
But Ursus was caught.
因为我，
Because of me,
他受苦了。但是我......
he suffered. But I...
你做了你必须做的事。
You did what you had to do.
我不知道我做了什么。
I don't know what I've done.
他需要我，我把他留在那里。
He needed me
and I left him there.
更多的罂粟酊剂。
More tincture of poppies.
-更多。- 够了，医生说。
- More.
- That's enough, the physician said.
你为我工作，而不是为医生工作。
You work for me,
not the physician.
我会服从医生为你工作。
I'll work for you by
obeying the physician.
不见了。而且没有这个乌尔苏斯的迹象。
It's gone. And no
sign of this Ursus.
我派他去看看金子是否还在。
I sent him to see if
the gold was still there.
这边。
This way.
老公。
Husband.
你不应该在这样的地方。
You shouldn't be in
a place such as this.
罗马女主人应该永远在丈夫身边。
A Roman matron should
always be at her husband's side.
不在这里。
Not here.
我试图获得提多的听众。他拒绝了。
I tried to obtain an audience
with Titus. He refused.
科妮莉亚？
Cornelia?
我试过了。她背对着我们。
I tried. She turned
her back on us.
我们误判了把她交给维斯塔尔对我们和朱利叶斯意味着什么。
We misjudged what giving her to the
Vestals would mean for us and Julius.
而对她来说。
And for her.
我与自己的命运和解了。
I'm reconciled to my fate.
我一定还能做些什么。
There must be
something else I can do.
-有。-什么？
- There is.
- What?
不要再来这里了，答应我。
Don't come here ever
again, promise me.
-不。- 想想我们的儿子。
- No.
- Think of our son.
保护自己和朱利叶斯的唯一方法就是谴责我。
The only way to protect yourself
and Julius is to denounce me.
不。
No.
你必须公开说话，叫我傻瓜。
You must speak
publicly, call me a fool.
篡位者。诅咒我的名字，
A usurper. Curse my name,
- 我疯狂的野心。-不。
- my mad ambition.
- No.
吐在我的坟墓上。
Spit on my grave.
- 告诉我的儿子也这样做。-不。
- Tell my son to do the same.
- No.
我怎样才能做这样的事情？不！
How can I do such things? No!
我们已经以我们庄严的家庭的名义牺牲了太多。
We've already sacrificed too much
in the name of our august families.
保护我们的名字是你的责任。
It is your duty to
protect our name.
你的名字，朱利叶斯的名字。
Your name, Julius' name.
我死了。
I'm dead.
如果你和他要茁壮成长，就必须被遗忘。
And must be forgotten if
you and him are to thrive.
铜椅不适合我。
The curule chair
was not meant for me.
但是朱利叶斯......等待你的时间。
But Julius... Bide your time.
让那些挡在你面前的人感到困惑。
Confound those who
would stand in your way.
比那些平民败类活得更久
Outlive those plebeian scum
看到我们的儿子登上皇权。
and see our son
risen to imperial power.
把我们的儿子放在铜椅上。
Put our son on the curule chair.
在那之后，他的儿子。
And his son after that.
- 停下来，你打伤了我。- 包扎伤口。
- Stop, you wound me.
- Bind your wounds.
让他们伤痕累累！
Let them scar!
转身离开我。
Turn from me.
拯救自己。
Save yourself.
救救我们的儿子。
Save our son.
我们的姓氏。
Our family name.
不，拜托，不！
No, please, no!
我已经忍住了足够长的时间。
I have held my
tongue long enough.
关于？
In respect of?
你从来没有骗过我。你误导了我。
You have never lied to
me. You have misled me.
你让我相信我的人民会自由
You had me believe that
my people would be free
当您的圆形剧场完工时。
when your amphitheater
was completed.
拜托，拜托，拜托，拜托。
Please, please, please, please.
足够。
Enough.
人们，他们被当作战利品。
People, they were
taken as a spoil of war.
他们现在属于罗马。
They belong to Rome now.
参议员们已经对他们的客户耳语了
Senators already
whisper to their clients
众神剥光了大地来惩罚我。
that the Gods stripped
the very earth to punish me.
你是说我？
You mean me?
也许，虽然主要是我，因为你把你当作我的配偶。
Perhaps, though mostly me,
for taking you as my consort.
你娶了一个妻子，把我放在阴影里。
You have taken a wife and
placed me in the shadows.
他们还能要求你什么呢？
What more can they ask of you?
他们要你走。
They want you gone.
没有另一个克利奥帕特拉的地方
There's no place
for another Cleopatra
毒害他们皇帝的耳朵。
poisoning the ear
of their emperor.
那是你哥哥在说话，不是你。
That is your brother
speaking, not you.
不，他已经证明了他对我的忠诚。
No, he's proven
his loyalty to me.
不。他说服了你他的忠诚。
No. He convinced
you of his loyalty.
他已经履行了他对我的责任，就像我必须履行我的职责一样。
He's fulfilled his duty to
me, just as I must fulfill mine.
所以我要等待
So I am to wait
当我的人民死在你们的建筑营地里时？
while my people die in
your construction camps?
不是现在。
Not now.
我有我的职责。
I have my duties.
如？
Such as?
罗马城。
The city of Rome.
你们中有人知道安东尼娅为什么召集这次会议吗？
Do any of you know why
Antonia called this meeting?
这有关系吗？
Does it matter?
马苏斯领事不会在这里。
Consul Marsus won't be here.
叛徒们正在他们真正属于的地方徘徊。
The traitors are languishing
away where they truly belong.
我亲爱的卡尔托尼亚，恐怕这次会议
My dear Caltonia,
I'm afraid this meeting
只适用于派系的主要所有者。
is only for the lead
owners of the factions.
虽然这么说让我很痛苦，但你可以走了。
Though it pains me
to say so, you may go.
你怎么敢？
How dare you?
你的丈夫因叛国罪入狱......
Your husband is
imprisoned for treason...
让我成为蓝色派系的主要所有者。
Making me lead owner
of the Blue Faction.
现在，走吧。
Now, go.
但在你走之前，亲爱的
But before you go, my dear
我希望你们都听到这句话。
I want you all to hear this.
我丈夫
My husband
背叛了罗马
has betrayed Rome
还有我们的皇帝。
and our emperor.
他应该为他的罪行而死。
He deserves to
die for his crime.
从这一刻起，我的丈夫对我们一家人来说已经死了。
From this moment on, my
husband is dead to our family.
他对我们的儿子朱利叶斯来说已经死了，
He's dead to our son, Julius,
他对我来说已经死了。
and he's dead to me.
你现在可以走了，卡尔托尼亚。
You may go now, Caltonia.
所以。。。
So...
让我们进入正题。
Let us get down to business.
什么？
What?
我想到了你前几天说的话。
I thought about what
you said the other day.
也许你是对的。
And maybe you are right.
也许我应该这样做
Maybe I should
偶尔玩得开心。
have fun once in a while.
天蝎座永远是对的。
Scorpus is always right.
那我们走吧。我们来喝一杯吧。
Let's go, then.
Let's get a drink.
老公，你要走了？
Husband, you're leaving?
我会让祭司祈祷，让占卜师为一个男孩举行仪式。
I'll have the priests pray and the
augurs perform the rituals for a boy.
现在，如果你快点，请立即通知我。
Now, if you quicken,
inform me immediately.
否则，下次准备好时，请在一个月内寄给我。
Otherwise, send for me in
a month when next ready.
打开。
Open.
我的母亲在我们很小的时候就去世了。
My mother died when
we were very young.
在那之前，我和我的双胞胎兄弟，
Until then, my
twin brother and I,
我们过着美好的生活。
we had a great life.
农场里有马和男孩梦寐以求的一切。
Farm with horses and
everything a boy dreams of.
但是，
But then,
在我母亲去世后，
after my mother's death,
我父亲开始喝酒，
my father began drinking,
后来，我哥哥也追随了他的脚步。
and later, my brother
followed in his footsteps.
他们因我无法理解的东西而结缘。
They bonded over stuff
I couldn't understand.
我不想明白。
I didn't want to understand.
嗯？是的。
Hmm? Yes.
你是什么时候开始参加比赛的？
When did you start racing?
我已经告诉过你了。我们俩很早就这样做了。
I already told you.
We both did early on.
但是我哥哥到处嫖娼，喝多了。
But my brother whored
around and drank too much.
他很好。
He was good.
他非常好。他比我好。
He was very good.
He was better than me.
赛道上的自然人。
A natural on the racetrack.
但。。。
But...
他缺乏纪律。
he lacked discipline.
就像你一样。
Just like you.
他叫什么名字？
What was his name?
塞克斯图斯。
Sextus.
是的，好吧，有这样的名字......
Yeah, well, with
a name like that...
你很有趣。
You're funny.
已经太多了。
Too much already.
当有理由庆祝时，人们应该庆祝。
When there's cause to
celebrate, one should celebrate.
所以你确定我们会获胜？
So you're certain
we will prevail?
我的律师很清楚。
My lawyers are clear.
你在蓝色派系的股份将是你的，然后是我的。
Your shares in the Blue Faction
will be yours, and then mine.
然后，你和你的儿子将拥有财富的安全感。
And then, you and your son
will have the security of wealth.
我不需要财富。
I don't need wealth.
你还太年轻，不知道。
You're too young to know that.
你知道，我们都需要不同的东西。
You know, we all
need different things.
渴望不同的东西。
Desire different things.
我们一起喝酒
We'll drink together
到我们需要的东西。
to the things we need.
还有我们想要的东西。
And the things we desire.
嗯？
Hmm?
卡尔托尼亚，我......
Caltonia, I'm...
允许我吗？
Allow me?
你以为我这么小吗？我会把自己卖给你吗？
You think that little of me?
That I will sell myself to you?
塞莱娜。。。
Selena...
请稍候。
Please, wait.
塞莱娜。
Selena.
我需要小便。
I need to take a piss.
这感觉很好。
That feels good.
喔！
Whoo!
来吧，它就在那里。
Come, it's there.
来。
Come.
- 萨莱娜。-原谅我。
- Salena.
- Forgive me.
我们无处可去。
We have nowhere else to go.
发生了什么事？
What happened?
我不能再呆在原地了。
I cannot stay where
I was anymore.
为什么？没关系，来吧。
Why? It doesn't matter, come.
过来这里。
Come here.
什么。。。
What...
他的名字叫费罗克斯。
His name is Ferox.
他像风一样快。
He's as fast as the wind.
这里。
Here.
我来这里是想说对不起。
I have come to
say that I am sorry.
你确定你不想杀我吗？
Are you sure you
don't want to kill me?
我从来不知道你。
I never know with you.
我希望你回到我们的蓝色阵营。
I want you to come
back to our Blue Faction.
出去。
Get out.
去。
Go.
我就知道你会回来的。
I knew you would come back.
我怎么能远离伟大的天蝎座呢？
How could I stay away
from the great Scorpus?
扶我起来。
Help me up.
不 不 不。现在这样做，你就会失去一条腿。
No, no, no. Do that
now and you lose the leg.
罂粟。
Poppies.
加油。
Come on.
中午更多。
More at midday.
我要去准备下注。
I'm going to go set
up for the betting.
对不起，伟大的天蝎座。
I'm sorry, great Scorpus.
但我不能让你为反对派骑马。
But I can't have you
ride for the opposition.
所以，你们都明白。
So, you all understand.
你仔细观察，看看谁刚刚迷路了，
You watch closely
to see who's just lost,
你悄悄地向他们提供反向赔率。
and you quietly offer
them reverse odds.
为此，我们每次下注都会得到一个 sesterce？
And for that we get
a sesterce every bet?
只要你不被抓住。
As long as you don't get caught.
天蝎座在哪里？
Where is Scorpus?
妈妈，没有人在赌金子
Mother, no one is betting gold
只有一辆黄金战车在运行。
with only one Gold
chariot running.
从Tenax订购。
Order from Tenax.
你们俩今天都在比赛。
Both of you are racing today.
什么？
What?
-我？- 嗯嗯。
- Me?
- Mm-hmm.
天蝎座呢？
What about Scorpus?
天蝎座无处可寻，我们需要两个司机。
Scorpus is nowhere to be
found, and we need two drivers.
你以为你得到了我，但我得到了你。
You thought you
got me but I got you.
祝你好运，兄弟们。像索尔本人一样骑行。
Good luck, brothers.
Ride like Sol himself.
冠军们，准备好了！
Champions, ready!
去，去，去，去！
Go, go, go, go!
移动，移动！
Move, move!
让开。
Get out of my way.
哎呀！
Hyah!
哎呀！哎呀！
Hyah! Hyah!
安德里亚！安德里亚！安德里亚！
Andria! Andria! Andria!
为什么天蝎座不骑马？
Why isn't Scorpus riding?
哎呀！哎呀！
Hyah! Hyah!
干得好，安德里亚！
Well done, Andria!
安德里亚！安德里亚！安德里亚！
Andria! Andria! Andria!
我喝醉了，我他妈的被蝎子咬了。
I was drunk and I was fucking
and I was bitten by a scorpion.
-不是我的错。-冷静。
- It's not my fault.
- Calm down.
很好。它减轻了你的压力。
It's good. It takes
the pressure off you.
我们会培训候补司机，以防您再次被咬伤
We train alternate drivers
in case you're bitten again
或者你喝醉了，或者你在做爱。
or you're drunk
or you're fucking.
互生？
Alternate?
互生？天蝎座没有替代品。
Alternate? There is
no alternate to Scorpus.
-是的。而且，没有。-是的。
- Well, yes. And, no.
- Yes.
你现在不仅仅是一个司机。
You're more than a driver now.
您是所有者。
You're an owner.
- 我们赢了。- 马屁。
- And we won.
- Horseshit.
这是你一直以来的计划吗？嗯？你要我走吗？
Was this your plan all along?
Hmm? You want me gone?
天蝎座。
Scorpus.
当然不是。
Of course not.
但比赛必须放在第一位，
But the racing
has to come first,
最近，
and recently,
看来你对喝酒和嫖娼更感兴趣。
it seems like you're more
interested in drinking and whoring.
你不明白。
You don't understand.
赛车的一部分是喝酒和嫖娼。
Part of racing is
drinking and whoring.
你不能没有其他的。
You cannot have
one without the others.
这是赛车，喝酒，嫖娼。
It's racing, drinking, whoring.
他们是一个团队。是的，就像马一样。
They are a team.
Yes, like the horses.
什么？
What?
赛车使我变得富有。
Racing made me rich.
我把我的名字改成了天蝎座，因为没有人能说出我的真名。
I changed my name to Scorpus because
nobody could pronounce my real name.
我喜欢喝酒。
I like to drink.
喝酒让我快乐。
Drinking makes me happy.
幸福让我想做爱，因为我出名了，
Happiness makes me want to
fuck, and because I am famous,
我可以操我喜欢的人。
I can fuck who I like.
唾弃这些礼物将是对福尔图纳的侮辱。
To spurn these gifts would
be an insult to Fortuna.
她诅咒我的驾驶，天蝎座已经不在了。
She curses my driving
and Scorpus is no more.
你打算什么时候交出我的那部分利润？
When were you planning to
hand over my portion of the profits?
我听说你已经死了。
I was told you were dead.
我不想发现谣言是真的，
I'd hate to discover
that rumor were true,
那么我的钱在哪里？
so where is my money?
我们的钱在哪里？
Where is our money?
我可以解释，殿下。
I can explain, Your Highness.
你的钱，我们的钱......
Your money, our money...
不见了。
is gone.
去向威胁要透露某事的人支付敲诈勒索......
Gone to pay extortion to someone
threatening to reveal something...
关于我？
About me?
不。
No.
我。
Me.
关于我的过去，
About my past,
在我来罗马之前。
before I came to Rome.
- 那是谁对你做的？-是的。
- That's who did this to you?
- Yes.
我不在乎你前世的尿液，
I don't care one piss
about your past life,
虽然我很难想象它比现在更糟糕。
though I struggle to imagine it
was worse than this present one.
我所关心的只是我需要的钱。
All I care about is
the money I need.
你欠我的钱。
The money that you owe me.
立即解决这个问题。
Solve this now.
否则我会让你受苦
Or I will make you suffer
以你的勒索者梦寐以求的方式。
in ways your extortionist
could only dream of.
还有你和他一起。
And you along with him.
我？
Me?
不 不。。。
No, no...
我做了什么？
What did I do?
顺便说一句，你看起来很糟糕。
You look terrible, by the way.
是的，我可以想象。
Yeah, I can imagine.
你想要一面镜子吗？
You want a mirror?
不，不，数字不符。
No, no, the numbers don't tally.
所以，你已经走了
So, you have gone
超越我最疯狂的梦想。
beyond my wildest dreams.
来这里，领取你的奖励。
Come here, collect your rewards.
没有变黑。
Hasn't gone black.
这很好。
Which is good.
罂粟花的酊剂在哪里？我一直在努力寻找它。
Where's the tincture of
poppies? I've been trying to find it.
这就是我隐藏它的原因。
Which is why I hid it.
- 把它拿给我。-不。
- Bring it to me.
- No.
你太过分了。
You overreach yourself.
我愿意。
That I do.
和
And,
我今天在比赛中也超越了自己。
I overreached myself at
the races today as well.
我们在铃声响起后下注。
We took bets after the bell.
什么？他们会让我们闭嘴的！
What? They'll shut us down!
冷静。我们没有被抓到。
Calm down. We weren't caught.
我承受不起这个风险。
I can't afford the risk.
也许你是对的。
Perhaps you're right.
从今天开始？
All from today?
好吧，好吧，只是不要被抓住。
All right, well, just
don't get caught.
去看看克劳迪娅，她会给你一些奖励。
And go and see Claudia,
she'll give you some rewards.
是的！
Yes!
我们需要重新谈判我们的协议。
We will need to
renegotiate our deal.
我病了。稍后再来。
I'm ill. Come back later.
你想要一些吗？很好。
You want some? It's good.
不,谢谢。这是给你的。
No, thank you. It's for you.
弗拉玛这次会拥有他。
Flamma will have him this time.
但福尔图纳偏爱努米底亚人。
But Fortuna favors the Numidian.
她饶过夸梅一次。12-1是有利的赔率。
She spared Kwame once.
12-1 are favorable odds.
即使在 100-1，你的非洲人也死了。
Even at 100-1,
your African is dead.
-请。-闭。
- Please.
- Closed.
开放是有价的。
Open for a price.
你需要什么？
What do you need?
阿特罗帕。
Atropa.
为什么大家都认为每家香水店都卖毒药？
Why does everyone think every
fragrance shop sells poisons?
这个确实如此。
This one does.
禁止毒药的法令是明确的。
The edict against
poisons is clear.
我必须是个傻瓜才能反对它。
I have to be a
fool to go against it.
你不是傻瓜。
You are no fool.
但也许你可能会对内线感兴趣。
But maybe an inside
line might interest you.
这条线。
The line.
明天押注夸梅对阵弗拉玛。
Bet on Kwame against
Flamma tomorrow.
这是一个愚蠢的赌注。
That's a fool's bet.
那是......
It was...
在你给我这个之前。
before you gave me this.
嘿 嘿！是的。
Hey, hey! Yeah.
弗拉玛，醒醒。
Flamma, wake up.
把他洗干净。
Wash him down.
我们希望他在哈迪斯之旅中保持最佳状态。
We want him to look his
best for his trip to Hades.
你不会匆匆忘记昨晚。
You won't forget
last night in a hurry.
我们必须走了。
We must go.
来，我们走吧。来。
Come, let's go. Come.
我让特纳克斯失望了。我必须解决这个问题。
I let Tenax down.
I've got to fix this.
我现在没有头脑。
I do not have a head
for this right now.
好吧，我会处理的。
All right, I'll take care of it.
- 我们会找到那个混蛋的。- 我们稍后再谈。
- We'll find that bastard.
- Let's talk about this later.
好，好。
Good, good.
装备努米底亚人。了。
Gear up the
Numidian. Time to die.
他不穿那种盔甲。
He doesn't wear
that kind of armor.
他现在这样做了，按照 Aedile Ludi 的命令。
He does now, on
order of the Aedile Ludi.
还不如把他扔给狮子。
Might as well throw
him to the lions.
你会把他钉在十字架上。
You'll crucify him.
他没有接受过这方面的训练。
He has not trained with this.
你为什么不告诉艾迪尔·鲁迪？
Why don't you tell
the Aedile Ludi that?
如果他反抗，就把他砍在人群看不见的地方。
If he resists, cut him
where the crowd can't see it.
- 你找到他了吗？-不。
- Did you find him?
- No.
一个浑身伤痕累累的熊那么大、丑陋的男人怎么会消失呢？
How can a big, ugly man the size of a
bear with scars all over just disappear?
我看到了这样一个人。
I saw such a man.
哪里？
Where?
在骨库附近的喷泉。到处都是伤疤。
At the fountain near the
ossuary. Scars everywhere.
跟我来。
Follow me.
我们向提图斯皇帝和玛西娅皇后致敬。
We hail Emperor Titus
and the Empress Marcia.
现在，我们来到我们的角斗士战斗。
Now, we come to our
gladiatorial combat.
再见了，我的兄弟。
Goodbye, my brother.
下辈子再见。
I will see you in the next life.
我们今天的第一场比赛......
Our first bout of the day...
请欢迎
Please welcome
伟大的弗拉玛。
the great Flamma.
弗拉玛！弗拉玛！弗拉玛！
Flamma! Flamma! Flamma!
谁将与狮子杀手夸梅战斗。
Who will fight the
lion killer Kwame.
万岁皇帝。
Hail Emperor.
我们，即将死去的人......
We, who are about to die...
向你致敬！
Salute you!
啊，来吧。
Ah, come on.
角斗士，准备好了吗？
Gladiators, ready?
今天是你死的时候了。
Today is your time to die.
向我致敬。
Honoring me.
聘！
Engage!
战斗，夸梅。战斗！
Fight, Kwame. Fight!
快点,快点。
Come on, come on.
狮子杀手夸梅！狮子杀手夸梅！
Lion Killer Kwame!
弗拉玛！弗拉玛！弗拉玛！
Flamma! Flamma! Flamma!
杀了他！
Kill him!
杀了他，弗拉玛！
Kill him, Flamma!
那个的角斗士怎么了？
What is wrong with
that bloody gladiator?
夸！夸！夸！
Kwame! Kwame! Kwame!
他流血了。他流血了！
He bleeds. He bleeds!
你认为自己是神吗？
You think yourself a God?
他抓住了他。
He's got him.
在你自己的马戏团里被屠杀。
Butchered in your own circus.
向上！向上！
Up! Up!
夸！夸！夸！
Kwame! Kwame! Kwame!
我成功了！
I did it!
-我成功了！-你做到了！
- I did it!
- You did it!
你不能永远躲着我，昆图斯。
You can't hide from
me forever, Quintus.
嗯。我已经准备好听听你需要说什么。
Hmm. I am ready to
hear what you need to say.
你是对的。
You are right.
我们确实需要谈谈。
We do need to talk.
母亲，我对你的尊重是无与伦比的
Mother, my respect
for you has no equal
我的爱人也没有。
and neither does my love.
但？
But?
但我不会回去。
But I will not go back.
那不是你的决定
That is not your decision
- 制作。- 但事实确实如此。
- to make.
- But it is.
除非你把我绑起来，把我拖回家，
Unless you bind me
and drag me home,
没有办法强迫我。
there is no way to force me.
你就像你的父亲一样。
You are just like your father.
夸梅也是。
Kwame, too.
还有朱拉......
And Jula...
我不知道朱拉是什么样的人。
I don't know who Jula is like.
朱拉就像朱拉。
Jula is like Jula.
父亲比你更了解我。
Father knew me
even better than you.
他曾经说过，鸟儿必须跟着羊群走。
He used to say birds
must follow their flock.
但是狮子，他找到了自己的道路。
But the lion, he
finds his own path.
- 但你是女人。-你也是。
- But you're a woman.
- So are you.
你找到了自己的路。现在我选择我的。
You found your path.
Now I am choosing mine.
-你去哪儿？- 去见朋友。
- Where are you going?
- To meet a friend.
在这个时候？谁？
At this hour? Who?
我选择不回答的问题。
A question I choose
not to answer.
我们关门了。
We're closed.
我说我们关门了。
I said we're closed.
他在哪？
Where is he?
我去了他家。
I went to his home.
他不在那里。
He wasn't there.
我给他留了一份礼物。
I left him a present.
我在这里等他。
I'll wait for him here.
但首先......
But first...
这可能比我想象的更有趣。
This might be more
fun than I thought.
你打算怎么处理？
What are you gonna do with that?
出去！你这个混蛋！
Get out! You fucker!
帮助！
Help!
慢慢死去。
Die slowly.
从哪里开始？
Where to start?
胸部？
The chest?
你的胃呢？
What about your stomach?
或者眼睛呢？
Or what about an eye?
是的。
Yes.
眼睛可能很好。
An eye might be good.
一只眼睛...
An eye...
为了一双眼睛。
for an eye.
我们回家吧。
Let's go home.